It was 1943. And young men were counting the days before they went off to war...
Racing with the Moon is a drama, romance film directed by Richard Benjamin.
In a small coastal California town, Henry and Nicky are pals from blue collar
families with only a short time before they ship off to World War II.
Henry begins romancing new-to-town Caddie Winger, believing her to be wealthy.
Mischievous and irresponsible, Nicky gets into trouble which forces the other two to become
involved, testing their relationship, as well as the friendship between the boys.
Henry 'Hopper' Nash, played by Sean Penn.
Nicky / Bud, played by Nicolas Cage.
Caddie Winger, played by Elizabeth McGovern.
Mr. Nash, played by John Karlen.
Mrs. Nash, played by Rutanya Alda.
Mr. Arthur, Piano Teacher, played by Max Showalter.
Racing with the Moon is a 1984 American drama film directed by Richard Benjamin, written by
Steve Kloves, and starring Sean Penn, Elizabeth McGovern and Nicolas Cage.
The original music score was composed by Dave Grusin.
The film's title derives from the 1941 hit song of
the same name by Vaughn Monroe.
In 2013, source music and elements of Grusin's score from the film were issued as additional
tracks on the CD release of Grusin's music for the soundtrack of  Heaven Can Wait.
The love theme, "A Secret Place", also appears on two Grusin recordings, Night Lines and
Now Playing, as well as being the title track of a Grover Washington, Jr.
release with Grusin playing piano on the session.
The tone is emotional.